W. Dean Mason Papers
W. Dean Mason Papers
1958-1980
Mason, W. Dean.
3 linear ft.
Papers of the American educator specializing in geriatrics and gerontology. Collection includes correspondence, speeches, reports, newsletters, and material relating to the National Geriatrics Society and to the Indiana Commission on Aging and Aged.
2628721
Biographical History
Wendell Dean Mason was an American educator, specializing in geriatrics and gerontology. He wrote or edited books and articles in his field, and was President of the National Geriatric Society.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The W. Dean Mason Papers contains material relating to gerontology, geriatrics, and nursing home administration with special emphasis on the Kennedy Memorial Christian Home in Martinsville, Indiana. Material includes correspondence, speeches, reports, newsletters, journals, surveys, press releases, clippings, memorabilia, and more. Organizations represented include the Adult Education Association, the National Council on Aging, the National Geriatric Society, and the Indiana Commission on Aging and Aged.
Arrangement of the Collection
The material remains in original order as received.
Subject and Genre Headings
Adult education; Mason, W. Dean -- Archives.; National Geriatrics Society.; Indiana. Commission on the Aging and Aged.; Kennedy Memorial Christian Home (Martinsville, Ind.); National Council on the Aging.; Adult education -- United States.; Geriatrics -- Research.; Geriatrics -- Study and teaching.; Nursing homes.; Correspondence.; Speeches (documents); Newsletters.; Reports.; Surveys (documents); Clippings (information artifacts); Press releases.; Geriatricians.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mrs. W. Dean Mason, 22 October 1982.
Inventory
- Box list
  - Curriculum vitae (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1980 (Box 1)
  - Speeches, printed, 1966-1977 (Box 1)
  - Reports, printed, various authors, 1958-1976 (Box 2)
  - Adult Education Association (Box 2)
  - Adult Education Association, relating to WDM's secretaryship of AEA (Box 2)
  - National Council on Aging, 1970s (Box 2)
  - Indiana Commission on Aging and Aged
    - Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 2)
    - Reports, 1970s (Box 2)
    - Indiana Regional Medical Program, 1975 (Box 2)
    - Human Services Personnel Association, 1974-1977 (Box 2)
  - National Geriatric Society
    - [Miscellaneous], 1970s (Box 3)
    - Conferences, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - Newsletters and journals, 1960s-1970s (Box 3)
    - Conferences
      - Middlers, 1969 (Box 3)
      - Wingspread, 1971 (Box 3)
      - White House, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Nursing homes
    - Kennedy Memorial, 1960s-1970s (Box 4)
    - Others (Box 4)
    - Reports, 1960s-1970s (Box 4)
    - Management desk book, 1972 (Box 4)
    - Surveys, 1960s-1970s (Box 4)
  - Nurses Training Program, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Press releases, 1970s (Box 5)
  - U.S. Government publications, 1966-1976 (Box 5)
  - Memorabilia (Box 5)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1960s-1970s (Box 5)
  - Periodicals, 1960s-1970s (Box 5)
  - Department of Education Title IA grant application, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Transactional Analysis for Managers (Box 5)
  - Related books and periodicals (Box 6)